yamaha-europe.com 2016-06-09

# Privacy Policy - Yamaha - Other European Countries

Data protection statement 

**Scope of application**   
This data protection statement explains to users the nature, scope and purposes of the collection and use of personal data that is performed by the provider responsible, Yamaha Music Europe GmbH, Siemensstraße 22-34, 25462 Rellingen (hereinafter referred to as "Yamaha") on this website (hereinafter referred to as the "services"). 

**Protecting your data**  
Yamaha believes that you have the right to know how this website collects and treats data, and would like to tell you how you can contribute to data protection. Essentially, it is possible to use the website without giving personal data. There may be different regulations for using specific services of our site, which we will explain separately below. The legal basis of data protection can be found in the German Federal Data Protection Act (BDSG) and the Telemedia Act (TMG). 

Each visit to a Yamaha website is automatically registered, where the visitor's IP address and domain name as well as the site that is visited are registered. Yamaha requires this information to understand how visitors are using the sites by employing statistical methods. This means the services can be continuously improved. 

**How does Yamaha use cookies?**   
You may also be asked for personal data in specific areas which may make it possible to identify you personally. The concept of personal data is defined in the German Federal Data Protection Act. It relates to particular details about personal or factual circumstances of a certain or determinable individual. In this regard, you will be asked to enter certain data, such as your name, your email address, postal address etc. These data are collected if you want to participate in certain services like chatrooms or forums, if you participate in a competition or if you request products or services using these internet services. 

Yamaha only collects these data for the respective purpose for which you give your personal data. To achieve this objective, Yamaha may pass on the data to its branch offices (e.g. to the respective national branch), who will process them. If the data are no longer required, we will destroy them in accordance with data protection law. If personal data are to be used beyond that, Yamaha will ask you expressly for your consent, which you can withdraw at any time by informing Yamaha. Your personal data will not be used for any other purpose than the one you have given it for without your consent. Beyond this purpose, they will also not be used to contact you and will not be passed on to third parties without your express consent. Should Yamaha be legally required to do so, it will pass on personal data to authorities or courts, upon request. 

**Security**   
Yamaha endeavors to ensure a high level of security of the website. Nevertheless, it is not possible to rule out unauthorized access to stored data or the system and the damage arising from this. 

**Data transfer** Your data will not be passed on to third parties, unless we are legally obliged to do so. Where external service providers come into contact with your personal data, we have ensured that these observe the provision of the data protection laws by means of legal, technical and organizational measures, in addition to regular monitoring. However, in these cases, the extent of the data being transferred is reduced to the minimum that is required. Your express consent is also required for transferring personal data to third parties, in particular if these third parties are located outside of the applicability of the law of the European Union. Consent can be withdrawn at any time with future effect. 

**Google Tag Manager**   
For reasons of transparency, we would like to inform you that we use Google Tag Manager. Google Tag Manager itself does not collect any personal data. Tag Manager makes it easier for us to integrate and manage our tags. Tags are small code elements that, among other things, are used to measure traffic and visitor behavior, to understand the effect of online advertising and social channels, to set up remarketing and orientation towards target groups, and to test and optimize websites. We only use Google Analytics (see below). If you have performed deactivation, Google Tag Manager takes this deactivation into account. For more information on Google Tag Manager see: [https://www.google.com/intl/de/tagmanager/use-policy.html ](https://www.google.com/intl/de/tagmanager/use-policy.html%20)

**Google Analytics**  
This website uses Google Analytics, web analysis service of Google Inc. ("Google"). Google Analytics uses text files, known as "cookies", which are saved on your computer and make it possible to analyze your usage of the website. The information about your use of the website generated by the cookie is generally transferred to a Google server in the USA, where it is saved. However, by activating IP anonymization on this website, your IP address is shortened by Google within Member States of the European Union or in other States party to the Agreement on the European Economic Area. The full IP address will only be transferred to a Google server in the USA and shortened there in exceptional cases. Google will use this information on behalf of the operator of this website to evaluate your usage of the website, to compile reports on the website activities, and to provide the website operator with additional services related to website and internet use. 

The IP address sent by your browser for Google Analytics will not be merged with other Google data. You can stop cookies being saved by amending the relevant setting in your browser software; however, we would like to point out that if you do this, you may not be able to use all of the functions of this website in full. Furthermore, you can stop the data generated by the cookie related to your usage of the website (including your IP address) being collected by Google, and stop Google processing these data by downloading and installing the browser plug-in available at the following link(<http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=de>). 

Alternatively, you can also prevent Google Analytics from collecting data by clicking on the following link. This creates an opt-out cookie, which stops your data being collected in the future when you visit this website: Deactivate Google Analytics. The opt-out cookie applies only to this browser and only to this domain. If you delete your cookies in this browser, you will need to click this link again. 

For more information on this, please see tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout and <https://www.google.de/intl/de/policies/> (general information on Google Analytics and data protection). See [www.google.com/privacy/privacy-policy.html](http://www.google.com/privacy/privacy-policy.html) for further information. 

**Newsletter**  
Our newsletter provides you with information about our products, promotions, campaigns and news. 

If you would like to receive the newsletter, we require a valid email address from you, as well as information that allows us to check that you are the owner of the email address given or that the owner agrees to receive the newsletter. No further data are collected. These data are only used to send the newsletter, and will not be passed on to third parties. 

When you register for the newsletter, we save your IP address and the date of registration. We only save this for evidence in the event that a third party misuses an email address, and registers for the newsletter without the knowledge of the entitled person. 

You can withdraw your consent to save the data, email address and the use of these to send the newsletter at any time. You can withdraw your consent via a link in the newsletter itself, in your profile or by sending a message using the contact details above. 

**Facebook, Google+ and Twitter social plug-ins**   
This website used social plug-ins of the following providers 

• Facebook (operator: Facebook Inc., 1601 S. California Ave, Palo Alto, CA 94304, USA)   
• Twitter (operator: Twitter Inc., 795 Folsom St., Suite 600, San Francisco, CA 94107, USA)   
• Google+ (operator: Google Inc., 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA) 

These plug-ins normally collect data from you as standard and transfer these to the server of the respective provider. 

To guarantee your privacy is protected, we have taken technical measures that guarantee your data cannot be collected by the provider of the respective plug-in without your consent. When accessing a site with integrated plug-ins, these are initially deactivated. The plus-ins are only activated by clicking the relevant symbol, and in doing you so give your consent for your data to be transferred to the respective provider. 

After activation, the plug-ins also collect personal data such as your IP address, and send these to the server of the respective provider, where they will be saved. Activated social plug-ins also create a cookie with a unique identifier when the website in question is accessed. Providers are thus also able to create profiles about your usage behavior. This also happens if you are not a member of the social network of the respective provider. If you are a member of the provider's social network and you are logged in to the social network while you visit this website, your data and information about visiting this website can be combined with your profile on the social network. We have no influence on the exact scope of the data collected about you by the respective provider. More detailed information on the scope, nature and purpose of data processing and on rights and settings options to protect your privacy can be found on the data protection notices of the respective social network provider. These can be found at the following addresses:

• Facebook: [http://www.facebook.com/policy.php ](http://www.facebook.com/policy.php%20)  
• Twitter: [http://twitter.com/privacy/ ](http://twitter.com/privacy/%20)  
• Google+: [http://www.google.com/intl/de/privacy/ ](http://www.google.com/intl/de/privacy/%20)

**Facebook Connect**   
We also offer the option of registering for our newsletter service with Facebook Connect. Additional registration is not required in this way. To register, you will be redirected to the Facebook site, where you can register with your user information. This connects your Facebook profile with our service. When these are connected, we will automatically receive the following information from Facebook Inc.: **Your name and email address.**

We will only use your name and email address out of these data. This information is essential to be able to identify you to send the newsletter. 

For additional information on Facebook Connect and the privacy settings, please see the data protection notices and usage terms of Facebook Inc. 

**Connecting with social media profiles**   
We offer the option of registering for our newsletter service with your social media profile. Additional registration is not required in this way. To register, you will be redirected to the respective social network, where you can register with your user information. This connects your profile with our service. When these are connected, we will automatically receive the following information: **Your name and email address.**

We will only use your name and email address out of these data. This information is essential to be able to identify you to send the newsletter. 

You can use the following social networks to connect your profile with us: - Facebook - Xing - Twitter 

For further information on connecting social network profiles and their privacy settings, please see the respective data protection notices and the usage terms of the social networks. 

**Competitions**   
You have the opportunity to participate in competitions on some of our websites. The data collected from you as part of participating in competitions are essentially only used for carrying out the competition, and we will then destroy it in compliance with data protection law. Participation in such campaigns is, of course, voluntary.

**Application process**   
If you submit an application to our company electronically, your details will only be used to process your application, and will not be passed on to third parties. Please note that applications you send us by email are transmitted unencrypted. 

**Data security**   
To protect your personal data that we have stored from unauthorized access and misuse, we have taken comprehensive technical and operational security precautions. Our security procedures are regularly inspected and adapted in line with technological advances. Our employees are regularly trained and are obliged to maintain data confidentiality. 

**Your rights**   
Transparency is very important to us. Upon request, we would be happy to tell you whether we have your personal data saved, and what these are, in accordance with our legal obligation. Under the requirements of the provisions of the German Federal Data Protection Act, you can request, if applicable, that these data be amended, blocked or deleted, provided this does not contravene legal retention periods. We would also be happy to provide you with our public register of processing operations, which contains the information required under Section 4g para. 2 in conjunction with Section 4e BDSG. Please contact us in this regard at: [TRitz@intersoft-consulting.de](mailto:TRitz@intersoft-consulting.de). 

If you have any questions relating to the processing of your personal data, you can also contact our data protection officer, who is also available to assist with requests for information, suggestions, or complaints. 

**Data protection officer contact details**   
If you have any queries, please contact:   
Personal/confidential F.A.O Mr Tim-Oliver Ritz  
intersoft consulting services AG  
Beim Strohhause 17  
20097 Hamburg

**Amendments to data protection notices**  
We reserve the right to alter and extend data protection notices. As at: March 2016
